Six years ago I started doing video full-time
Six years later I have a team that's almost
but not yet twenty people
and two villas
Yes, I've fitted out another villa
Doing self-media
I still have a lot of passion
a lot of desire
Last year's room tour
I introduced our studio
how much money we spent on hardware
Today I want to share with you more specifically
how I make videos
what's different about making videos now compared to six years ago
and what plans I have going forward
Right as you enter you can see a big
Tanwan PLAYFULL
Not "NING" anymore
We'll talk about this later
First let's take a look at my newly fitted garage
This time it's not a hidden door
there's an actual door
Pretty sci-fi, huh
Push it open
I've long wanted to have a
sci-fi feeling
and clean SET
Now let's chat
Everyone surely knows
the general process is
But I've found
this is a bit different from five or six years ago
still not quite the same
First is topic selection
Back then the main focus was sincere sharing
topic selection looked inward
But now
long videos are increasingly like old-school TV programs
So back then
creators were easily worried
Creative inspiration drained and squeezed dry
Nothing left to output or share
But look at how much content is out on the market right now
Too much to even get through watching it all
AI can even directly help you pick topics
For example
You can have GPT imitate Linus Tech Tips to come up with some topic ideas
Look, it thought for 37 seconds
And spat out dozens of topic ideas
Let me read two of them out
Pretty convincingly done, actually
Or
You can also use Claude to imitate Xiao Ningzi for topic ideas
Quite interesting
I think it's better than the one imitating LTT
But this "internet observation" category is just way too absurd
These topics can't be used directly
But they're still quite inspiring
Then comes scriptwriting
Back in the day, a 5-minute video was already considered pretty long
But now for long-form videos
The standard spec is basically around 10 minutes
Some go even longer
As for the specific process
Like this room tour video you're watching right now
I first lock down the title
Which is the main question my video wants to answer
Then I write the outline
What specific topics the video will cover
Because it's a room tour
I also have to consider at the same time
Whether its circulation path is smooth
And then explain those topics clearly
Of course, this is the most basic structure of a video
As you all know
Our channel's videos are a bit special
Niche but not that niche
Spanning tech, digital, gaming, DIY, science popularization, and life
Plus music
The type of video being made differs
The focus of the writing should also be different
Is to properly explain one matter clearly
Or to mess around and play with memes
Or is live reaction needed on site
And also those kinds of re-production, re-shooting, re-stage-managing ones
There is a bit of everything
For me, a lot of the experiences are very fresh
There is pressure but it is also quite fun
Of course, this also means
The difference from most bloggers in the digital zone is
Our aroll shooting
Actually every time requires re-setting the scene
Right now this is an empty room that has not been arranged
Turn it into a space that can be shot
Generally three steps are needed
The first step
Find a suitable background
Create a sense of depth as much as possible
Best to have a feeling of the passage of time
That is, there are windows
After finding it
The second step
For this episode's video I need to convey a sense of approachability
Better to add some scene lights
Finally
There is shaped light in the scene
Key light
Rim light
And the sun
Then we can shoot
Five years ago the cost of making videos was relatively low
Many people made videos while also working their day jobs
Back then
The audience's choices were also relatively fewer
But now
The production cost of the entire industry is rising
Only with a source of income can one keep making videos
Taking on commercial commissions
Apart from content creation
The ability that must be learned and mastered
What everyone imagines doing commercial commissions to be like
is different from what doing commercial commissions is actually like
Some things you assume are commercial commissions
really aren't commercial commissions
Especially in the gaming category
For example, a while back
the game *Wuchang: Fallen Feathers* that got creators cursed for "selling out for dirty money"
As far as I know
99%
were not commercial commissions
There was no money received
Really, no money was taken
Another thing that's rather mind-bending is
a commercial commission video does not equal one that's meant to sell products
The clients' demands are bizarre and varied
Some do want to sell products
but there are also those who want brand publicity
want to promote a certain kind of technology
want to do something viral and break out of their circle
or just want a certain word repeated over and over
All of it exists, everything exists
So a good commercial commission is hard to come by
It's already not easy to hit it off at first try
Like this time, the one that supported my studio's infrastructure build-out
the Haier Mai Lang Comfort Wind Pro air conditioner
goes well with my rather industrial-retro-style office
And the owner of this office
is the one who appeared in previous videos
that girl who plays the guitar
named Xiao Tang
is my brand partner
Although we've already launched our first wave of products
we actually never properly introduced ourselves to everyone
So actually
Tanwan PLAYFULL
is a creative brand we founded last year, in 2024
on May 6th
and then on this year's June 5th
officially launched
I had two initial intentions for doing Tanwan PLAYFULL
One is that walking on multiple legs is certainly healthier.
The second is that I have many designs that I like.
I simply couldn't buy them anywhere.
And then I just thought, um…
I want it  I got it
So I brought in Xiao Tang as my product partner.
And Guan'er, who is in charge of the e-commerce division.
Together we set out to do this.
This is the live-streaming area specially prepared for PLAYFULL.
The meaning of PLAYFULL is Play to the fullest.
Play until you're full, play until you're stuffed, play to your heart's content.
Here we display the clothing we have already launched.
For example, the Logo Tee.
And the colorful button-up shirt that I like very much.
Making clothes sounds very simple.
But actually,
It took us a full year to prepare.
These here are some behind-the-scenes tidbits.
Can you tell apart these shades of yellow,
And what distinguishes these purples?
Also the buttons here—
When we were selecting the buttons back then,
It was a pile of buttons and
My favorite chocolate beans.
I was comparing them right there.
The set we finally chose is this group.
Its color, shape, and size
Were all carefully selected.
What gave us the longest headache
Was that T-shirt with the large graphic on the back.
The more complex the graphic,
The more painful the iteration process.
Here is truly just the tip of the iceberg.
Front and back, including the style,
Dozens of versions—
All of them existed.
Then there is the choice of craftsmanship.
We basically chose
The best craftsmanship within our means.
My first time participating in it.
Only then did we realize that making a piece of clothing is no easy task
But with these attempts
We became a bit bolder
Directly
Directly went so far as to designing our own storage pouches ourselves
This model
Is a style we recently finalized
Why did we think of using embroidered patches
Is because when we ourselves use storage pouches
We very much want to stick some things on them
Favorite patterns
But they are not an official standard configuration
And they were not put through unified design either
So this time, based on PLAYFULL's style
We designed a set of game-themed embroidered patches
They can be stuck on directly
You take them off and can stick them right on
Especially convenient
Especially cute
I especially like this little sword
It is too cute
Orange-and-blue colorway
And orange-and-white colorway
These are all
Discarded proposals
We would feel
Orange might not be particularly mainstream
And this red, if you look closely
You will find there is actually a color difference here
That is not OK
This model, actually, someone in our studio
Likes it very much
I do not know if everyone will like it
Whether you prefer the classic red-and-white colorway
Or would like this more unconventional
Younger colorway
Mm
Making storage pouches
We feel the most important thing first is function
After opening it
Uh, we actually first ensure
The Switch 2 is placed inside and is very safe
We've done a lot of designs like this, they all exist
Secondly
That is
There can be a simple mesh pocket to put things
And also some cartridge storage
Although now the Switch 2 also, um
Cartridges aren't used particularly much, ah
Aside from function, the storage case
Its choice of auxiliary materials is also very important
Because it reflects the texture and feel
Here are all the webbing materials we've selected
Each kind is different
For the zipper pull choice we also picked several kinds
Ultimately we chose what I think is the Switch 2
Its自带 original storage case
The circular ring handle inside
Is the easiest to pull
That is, it has the greatest pulling force
The whole bag has been carefully researched
From function to appearance to materials
If you let me in the vast sea of the market
Choose a Switch 2 storage case
I would choose our own PLAYFULL
Finally, the docking station three-piece set
Currently this project is still under confidentiality
There isn't much we can share with everyone yet
Here there will be some of our early design sketches
If it can successfully launch
This will be the first electronic product we've made
I'm really looking forward to it
We will also use 3D printing to make some models
To see the effect
So far it looks pretty good
Also, it has already iterated
This many color schemes
Can't reveal too much to everyone
In short this will be my most most anticipated
Most most liked product
I hope it can be made available to everyone as soon as possible
As for the new villa, I actually only renovated the necessary live-streaming rooms
Two sets
One office
One meeting room
And one good-looking toilet
Renovated as needed
The rest are all bare-shell units
Yet to be developed
Finally, thanks to Haier Mailang Comfort Wind Pro air conditioner
For the sponsorship of this video